<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Passwords on Unlogic </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/tags/passwords/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>I made this: Purplescraper</title>
      <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/05/14/i-made-this-purplescraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/05/14/i-made-this-purplescraper/</guid>
      <description>Had this script sitting around for a while and I figured I would clean it up a bit and share it. Get Purplescraper from my Github In short: you give it a starting directory, which will usually be where all the user directories are, and it will go get all .purple/accounts.xml files and extract any usernames and passwords it finds into a new file. Useful to make sure none of your sensitive data is available to other, non authorised users via slack file permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting strong passwords</title>
      <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/04/14/revisiting-strong-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/04/14/revisiting-strong-passwords/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I wrote a post about strong passwords. That was three years ago and I figured I might as well revist what I wrote back then. Since then technology has moved on a lot, and the number of password breaches has increased, aswell as the number of reports mocking our poorly chosen passwords. As far as I am concerned, I am still using 15-18 random character passwords. I&amp;rsquo;m no longer lowercase only, but a mixture of upper, lower, digit, and punctuation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong passwords?</title>
      <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/2012/06/06/strong-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unlogic.co.uk/2012/06/06/strong-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m just going around and updating the passwords to some of my online accounts, which was prompted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=no&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;u=http://www.dagensit.no/article2411857.ece&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article, I was wonderingwhat a good password really is. Not just in terms of security but also in terms of user friendliness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

