<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gear Vr on Unlogic</title>
    <link>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/tags/gear-vr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gear Vr on Unlogic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/tags/gear-vr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I think Gear VR is the way forward</title>
      <link>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/2015/02/10/why-i-think-gear-vr-is-the-way-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/2015/02/10/why-i-think-gear-vr-is-the-way-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to try out and work with the DK2 and the Samsung
GearVR, and while both do what they do really well, I much prefer my experience
with the GearVR. This isn&amp;rsquo;t down to a technical advantage like improved
resolution, or the way it looks, it&amp;rsquo;s about the experience. I&amp;rsquo;ve strapped on the
DK2 more times that I can remember, and I&amp;rsquo;ve set it up as many times too. I hate
setting it up. There&amp;rsquo;s a plethora of cables. You have a USB cable for the headset
and one for the tracking camera. Then there&amp;rsquo;s a cable to connect the
tracking camera to the headset line. Add a power supply and a HDMI lead and
you&amp;rsquo;re now totalling 5 plugs you need to connect to set it up. Then you need
to configure the headset, making sure that the setting for the desktop are correct.
Some apps need direct to DK2, others need the dekstop extended, except when you
are on Windows 8, where it always needs to be extended. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to work
myself up just writing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So enter the GearVR. The empty headset lands on my desk and I unpack it. It looks
like a something a strom trooper would strap to their face. It&amp;rsquo;s light. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s
no phone in it yet. We order a Samsung Note 4 and once it arrives I go about setting
it up and installing all the necessary software. The SD card that comes with the headset
contains all the required software to get you started and once the main software is
installed, you can install more via its built-in store/library. So I clip the phone into
the headset and put it on. It&amp;rsquo;s still much lighter than the DK2, so I hope that the new
Rift will be a little bit lighter too. The interface is clean and easy to use. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
got a gamepad, so I use the onboard swipe based controller and buttons to navigate.
It all works like a charm. But wait, there&amp;rsquo;s something weird&amp;hellip;. that&amp;rsquo;s right, not
a single cable in sight. I can actually get up and walk around in it. Disclaimer:
that&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea, stay put! I like the interface, it all seems very straightforward
and natural. The only issue I have is that my arm gets fatigued after a while of
having to hold it up to the side of the headset where the touchpad is. But I can
take it off and put it down without having to manage any cables, or worry about
getting caught up in a lead with my chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically I can unclip the front, insert the phone, put it on, and get going.
Once connected to the headset, the phone automatically launches the VR software,
and it only plays if you have the headset on (there&amp;rsquo;s a sensor inside for that).
It&amp;rsquo;s as easy as that. This to me is a big win over something like the Oculus. Sure
the Rift has the power of a high end gaming PC behind it, but I still prefer to
experience this new world of VR through the Samsung GearVR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately skirted around resolution, content and the like because those
are variable and to me, the big difference that made the GearVR more enjoyable to
use was how easy it was to setup and the lack of cables. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got a station
where you want to keep your VR setup, then the Rift will be a better choice, no
doubt. If however you want to play games, or watch movies whereever and whenever,
and not have to fiddle around with a mess of cables, then the GearVR is unbeatable.
And right now, the display quality on the GearVR beats the DK2 IMO. I imagine
that the next Rift will be on par though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>