<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Linux on Unlogic </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/tags/linux/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting bup files in Linux</title>
      <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/09/03/extracting-bup-files-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/09/03/extracting-bup-files-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>I recently got hold of some malware that got snapped up by McAfee and stored in a bup file. Keen to take a look at it, I researched how to &amp;lsquo;unbup&amp;rsquo; files and found this page: http://blog.opensecurityresearch.com/2012/07/unbup-mcafee-bup-extractor-for-linux.html A slow bash script? A faster script in Perl? No, that won&amp;rsquo;t do. Rather than search for a Python implementation I decided to use this as an opportunity to write something, and thus my unbup.py was born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joys of server ownership</title>
      <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/05/08/the-joys-of-server-ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unlogic.co.uk/2015/05/08/the-joys-of-server-ownership/</guid>
      <description>This post serves mostly as a &amp;ldquo;note to self&amp;rdquo;. I just ordered myself a super cheap VPS from Ramnode as I have a little project I would like to setup and see if I can make it work. But first I had to setup the server (Debian 7.0) and it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve done that, so some reading was in order to remind myself of all the joys. Thus I decided to note this down for myself and anyone else who&amp;rsquo;s interested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim clang autocompletion</title>
      <link>http://unlogic.co.uk/2012/07/13/vim-clang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unlogic.co.uk/2012/07/13/vim-clang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Code completion. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it nice? Especially when you have a so many APIs that you can&amp;rsquo;t always remember EVERY method, member or class name in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it powerful? The ease and speed with which it allows you to edit your code and do your work is just lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But code completion in vim? Well yes. You can use ctags. Yes, you can make tag files for ALL your APIs and autocompletion works rather well. I did this and the Qt tags file is 1.7GB. So, urm yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely awesome either. Plus it doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle things like smart pointers, which you will no doubt come across at some stage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

