<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Unlogic</title>
    <link>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Unlogic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 20:18:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Back it up</title>
      <link>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/2014/02/26/back-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 20:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/2014/02/26/back-it-up/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been paying for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt; in order to ensure
my photos, music, and other import data doesn&amp;rsquo;t get lost in a hard drive crash, theft or fire.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I really need to go over all the reason why you should backup your data, do I?
But you should at least have a local backup, and ideally an offsite one too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I stop paying for Backblaze? No real reason. It came up to the renewal date
and I thought &amp;ldquo;I wonder if I can do this a little cheaper perhaps?&amp;rdquo;. After all, I&amp;rsquo;m not
a stranger to technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Christmas I was lovingly gifted a 2TB
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wdc.com/en/products/products.aspx?id=280&#34;&gt;WD Mybook Live drive&lt;/a&gt;
and thought this is what I will use for backups (amongst other things). To give you
an overview of what I need to backup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Around 40GB of photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of photos, after all, I&amp;rsquo;m no professional, but those that I do
take are dear to me. So they need to be backed up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;MP3s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I actually have those on Google Play, so they are already kinda backed up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few MB of documents&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual stuff like invoices, receipts, correspondence, etc&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few GB of code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s what I do. So there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of it, and not all of it is on Github.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all spread across an old iMac I rarely use and a MacBook Pro which is my
daily use machine. I also want to have a local backup and an offsite backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first off I had to pick some software that will at least copy the relevant files
to the WD and create snapshots as a bonus. Because I&amp;rsquo;m an old command line lover, I
first opted for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/rdiff-backup/&#34;&gt;rdiff-backup&lt;/a&gt; which, after some
set up and testing, worked really well. I&amp;rsquo;d run the backup whenever I changed some
important files, or at least once a week. Then, on Sunday I would rsync the backup onto
a memory stick which I always have with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was fine until my connection dropped in the middle of
a backup operation. What happens then is that the target dir is corrupt and rdiff-backup
tries to roll back the recent backup. Which is fine in most cases, but in my case something
got stuck and it never completed the roll back.
I blew the directory away and started again, during which I looked at some alternatives (free),
seeing as I now had some time to kill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I thought &amp;ldquo;I can give this Time Machine thing a try. After all, it&amp;rsquo;s free and
it&amp;rsquo;s built right into the OS (sorta)&amp;ldquo;. For some reason though it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me select a mount
as a backup target. Probably because they don&amp;rsquo;t want you backing your local disks to
your local disks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was out of the question. Then I thought I would checkout &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashplan.com&#34;&gt;Crashplan&lt;/a&gt;
as they were always coming up as an alternative to Backblaze and is also cross platform.
I checked out their free service which allows you to backup to a remote host, and
conveniently it also supports backing up to local folders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I downloaded it, did a basic setup and fired it off, along with an up-to-date
rdiff-backup. Both take a little bit of time as it&amp;rsquo;s the first backup, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t
bother me much, the incrementals will be quicker. What I wanted to know was how big the
backup will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly Crashplan&amp;rsquo;s initial backup is over 1GB less than the rdiff-backup. I imagine
that it will get bigger, as I have it set to keep a longer history, but still, that&amp;rsquo;s
quite a saving. It also runs in the background, so no manual intervention needed.
It&amp;rsquo;ll just tick along and backup behind the scenes just like Backblaze did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my offsite, I&amp;rsquo;ll still use my USB stick with rdiff-backup mostly because
I need to copy the data onto a remote machine with rsync. Crashplan creates a single file for the backup
which will be a pain to copy each time. Using rsync to copy off an rdiff backup is
much quicker after the initial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary:452007e1b02afdfb52b4409ed9fffdbd&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically I am now running Crashplan locally having left Backblaze. I will say
that I would have stayed with Backblaze if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t prone to tinkering and I
wasn&amp;rsquo;t averse shelling out a bit extra for a family plan. As it is, I can now
backup all the machines in the house for the price of nothing
(plus hardware accessories ;))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve only been running it for a day so far, so time will tell if it&amp;rsquo;s as good
Backblaze, but so far this is the backup solution I am going with. I&amp;rsquo;ll update
this post with any discoveries if they are minor, or write new posts if they
require a bit more space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>