<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conky on Unlogic</title>
    <link>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/tags/conky/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conky on Unlogic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/tags/conky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tube status for Conky</title>
      <link>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/2012/06/07/tube-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://svenito.github.io/nowhere/2012/06/07/tube-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I was affected by &amp;ldquo;severe delays on the Central line&amp;rdquo; caused by a burst watermain and bringing part of the line to its knees. Unfortunately I only found this out once I got to the station. Usually the line is well behaved and I have little need to check it often. I know it&amp;rsquo;s really quick to do so and there&amp;rsquo;s a whole host of ways to dit too. But the problems I have with them are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check online&lt;/strong&gt;: Have to remember to go online and check, which I often/always forget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPhone app&lt;/strong&gt;: Same again. Have to remember to actually do that each time I leave the office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email alerts&lt;/strong&gt;: I get a fair bit of email each day and end up just clicking &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;mark as read&lt;/em&gt; on stuff like that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CLI app that checks the tube status for any number of given lines. &amp;ldquo;Yeah, how does that help?&amp;rdquo; I hear you ask. &amp;ldquo;You still have to use it to check it&amp;rdquo; you say. True. But there&amp;rsquo;s another way to use it: Conky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://conky.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Conky&lt;/a&gt; and I love it. So what better than to have the tube status for the relevant lines &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; on my desktop and updating every few seconds? So I quickly put together this python script to accomplish the task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 2888187 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;center%20/images/content/conky.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To add it to Conky just edit the &lt;code&gt;.conkyrc&lt;/code&gt; file and add a line like so: &lt;code&gt;$alignr${execi 2 /path/to/tube.py central -s}&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;em&gt;central&lt;/em&gt; is the name(s)  of the line(s) (separate multiple lines with spaces) you want to get statuses for. The full list of lines is &lt;a href=&#34;http://tubeupdates.com/documentation/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The -s simply tells the script to supress the output of the full message and shows only the line name and short status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be good to know if you find it useful or if you have any suggestions for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>